A Guide to the Slaughter B. Bullock Papers, 1760-1910
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Slaughter B. Bullock Papers, 1760-1910
The Library of Virginia
23932
10 leaves and 29 pages
Slaughter B. Bullock
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
From Katherine L. Bullock of Richmond, Virginia, 19 February 1953.
Biographical Information
Slaughter B. Bullock was born 17 February 1813 in Spotsylvania County, Virginia, to James (1760-1836) and Sarah Bullock (1775-1842). He married Louisa W. Vaughan (b. 1819) 23 March 1837 and they had 8 girls and 2 boys. Bullock was a farmer in Spotsylvania County, then in the 1850s, he moved his family to Hanover County, Virginia, where he continued to farm. After the Civil War, he began work as a carpenter. Slaughter B. Bullock died 2 March 1883.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1760-1910, of Slaughter B. Bullock (1813-1883) of Spotsylvania and Hanover Counties, Virginia, consisting of Bullock family Bible records, 1760-1910; deeds, 1832-1856, for all right, title, and interest in the estate of John Sale, and for property in Spotsylvania and Hanover Counties; receipts, 1837 and no date, for payment for Esther Sale's board and for payment of tuition for Bullock's daughters; minutes, 20 October 1856, of the Independence Meeting House regarding a quarrel involving Bullock; Confederate bonds, 1863; account of sale, 23 September 1863, of property belonging to Bullock; account, April-August 1864, of Bullock as administrator of the estate of John W. Smither (d. ca. 1864); agreements, 1865 and 1873, between Bullock and his former slaves, and between Bullock and W. R. Winn for legal matters; Bullock's oath of allegiance to the United States, 15 August 1865; an unidentified fragment, no date; and a document pouch.
Contents List
- Bullock family Bible records, 1760-1910.
- Deed, 1 January 1832, from Robert Sale to Albert G. Sale for all right, title, and interest in the estate of their father John Sale.
- Receipt, 10 January 1837, from John C. Sale to Francis Sale, guardian of Esther Sale acknowledging payment for Esther's board.
- Deed, November 1855, for 55 3/4 acres of land in Spotsylvania County from Bullock and his wife Louisa to William Stanley (d. 1879), deed is incomplete.
- Deed, dated 19th February 1856 and recorded 25 March 1856, for 257 acres in Hanover County between T. S. Kilby of the first part, C. B. Jones of the second part, and Samuel H. Tinsley of the third part.
- Meeting minutes, 20 October 1856, at Independence Meeting House in Hanover County regarding the quarrel between Bullock and the Reverend William A. Dick.
- Bonds, 9 April 1863, from the Confederate government to Bullock, 2 for $1000, 1 for $2000, and 1 for $3000.
- Account of sale, 23 September 1863, of property belonging to Bullock.
- Account, April-August 1864, of Bullock as administrator of the estate of John W. Smither (d. ca. 1864).
- Agreement, 17 June 1865, between Bullock and his former slaves, in which Bullock pays wages and provides board for his former slaves in return for their labor.
- Oath of allegiance, 15 August 1865, to the United States of Bullock, stating he is a resident of Mecklenburg County, Virginia.
- Agreement, 27 August 1873, between W. R. Winn and Bullock for Winn to handle some legal matters for Bullock.
- Receipt, no date, from Sarah W. Smith to Bullock for payment of tuition for his daughters.
- Unidentified fragment, no date.
- Document pouch.